钱德，你做得很不错，马上就要结婚…
Chandler, you're doing so well with this whole getting married...
…以后不和其他人睡觉．太好了
...never gonna sleep with anyone for the rest of your life thing. I thinks it's great.
谁要法国吐司? 给我一点
- Hey. Who wants French toast? - I'll have some.
我也要，牛奶和鸡蛋在冰箱里，谢谢
Me too. Eggs and milk in the fridge. Thanks.
怎么回事? 我的手怪怪的
- What's the matter? - My hand feels weird.
因为订婚的关系吧!
I guess it's because I'm engaged!
什么时候会开始变得烦人? 开始?
- When will that start getting annoying? - Start?
开始计划婚礼吧
Let's start the wedding plans.
好    现在就开始?
- Okay. - Already?
有很多事要做，要想花的安排，音乐…
We got a lot to do. We gotta think about the flowers, the music...
我觉得音乐的安排．钱德，已经很多计划了
- I have thoughts on the music... - Chandler. Too many cooks.
给你一个过来人的建议 你只需要出现，说对名字就好了
Take it from me. All you have to do is show up and try to say the right name.
那是什么? 老天，是婚礼计划书?
- What in God's name is that? - Oh, my God, the wedding book?
四年级后我就没看到它了
I haven't seen that since fourth grade.
这里面什么都有，比如说：地点
This baby has everything. Take, you know, locations, for instance:
先以字母顺序排列 再以地理位置排列...
First organized alphabetically, then geographically...
然后以场地大小排列
...then by square footage.
好聪明
That is so smart.
快溜，快溜，就是现在
Break it off. Break it off now.
看，这是你五年级和约翰・林奇结婚的请柬
Look, here's the invitation you used to your wedding to John Lynch in the fifth grade.
还记得我病了，罗斯顶替当伴娘吗?
Remember how I got sick and Ross had to fill in as a bridesmaid?
我是伴郎
I was a brides-boy.
我还没闻到法国吐司的味道，伴郎
I don't smell French toast, brides-boy.
Friends S07E02 瑞秋的书
The One With Rachel's Book
以上证明了…
That conclusively proves...
《侏罗纪公园》是我先想到的
...that I had the idea for Jurassic Park first.
我们来看看…
Let's take a look...
菲比，你来干什么?
Phoebe, what are you doing here?
我有事和你说，很紧急，有关莫妮卡和钱德
I need to talk to you. It's urgent. It's about Monica and Chandler.
我的天，当然
Oh, my God. Of course.
等我一下
Would you please excuse me for a moment?
你们知道彼此从哪儿来的吗? 何不…?
Do you know each other's hometowns? Why don't you...?
怎么回事?
What's going on?
没什么，我在想他们刚订婚…
Well, not much. I was just thinking that since they just got engaged...
应该多给他们一些独处的时间
...it would be nice if they have privacy.
我可以搬去你家几天吗?
So could I just move in with you for a couple days?
好，当然，莫妮卡和钱德发生了什么事吗?
Okay, sure. But what's wrong with Monica and Chandler?
没事，怎么了?
Nothing. Why?
你说很紧急的
Phoebe, you said it was urgent.
是啊，我的电影5分钟后要开演了
Yeah, it is. My movie starts in, like, five minutes.
你知道我有一屋子的学生在这儿吗?
Do you realize I have a classroom full of students?
抱歉，我很没礼貌 有人想要一起去看电影吗
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm so rude.Does anyone want to come to the movies?
我还没和爸妈谈到预算…
I haven't cleared the budget with my parents...
不过音乐部份的安排这样好不好?
...but tell me how this is for music:
行进时用弦乐四重奏  鸡尾酒会时安排爵士乐三重奏
A string quartet for the processional, a jazz trio for cocktails...
跳舞时用湾市摇滚（七八十年代的合唱团）…
...the Bay City Rollers for dancing...
等一下，那是我的六年级婚礼
Wait, that was for my sixth grade wedding.
也不可能用他们  伊恩不演出了，德瑞克…
You couldn't get them anyway. Lan doesn't even play anymore and Derek...
我不该知道德瑞克这个人的
Derek is a name I shouldn't know.
莫妮卡，有没有别的枕头比较舒服一点的?
Mon, do you have another pillow, something a little snugglier?
你为什么不回去你家，要在这里睡?
Why are you napping here instead of at your place?
-因为鸭子 -什么，鸭子?
- The duck. - What... The duck?
现在那该死的鸭子又做了什么?
What the hell did the damn duck do now?
它没有到处呕吐…
Well, he did not get sick somewhere in there...
而且立刻被发现，并妥当处理干净了
...and it was immediately found and properly cleaned up.
我可以看吗…
Do I get to look at this book...
还是只有婚礼相关人员可以看?
...or is it just for people involved in the wedding?
你当然可以看，我要你的意见
Of course you can look at it. I want your opinion.
来
Here you go.
桌子中间的花饰? 桌子中间的花饰!
- What about centerpieces? - Centerpieces!
玫瑰还是百合？ 当然是玫瑰
- Roses or lilies? - Definitely roses.
我觉得它们比较像婚礼用花
I think they're more "wedding-y."
但很清楚应该选百合 老天，简直就是同一个脑袋
- But lilies are the clear choice. - Oh, my God, it's like one mind.
各位，各位，让我休息好不好
Guys, guys, you gotta let me nap.
不然我会脾气不好
I'm gonna get cranky.
乔伊，走廊对面有很好的沙发
Joey, there's a perfectly good couch across the hall.
是很不错…
Yes, it is perfectly good...
但那不是鸭子呕吐的地方之一
...and it is not one of the places the duck got sick.
什么?
What?
好，我要走了 乔伊，鸭子到底做了什么
- All right, I'm gonna go. - Joey, what did the duck do?
我不知道，但它没吃你的面霜
I don't know, but he did not eat your face cream.
小朋友，你觉得如何?
Hey, little buddy. How you feeling?
那面霜里到底有什么?
What the hell is in that face cream?
好软
That's so soft.
有枕头套耶!
Pillowcases!
“柔达看着扫烟囱的人 她的父亲是个传教士…”
"Zelda looked at the chimney sweep. Her father, the vicar..."
传教士?
Vicar?
还有好几小时才会回来
"...wouldn't be home for hours.
她欲火中烧
Her loins were burning.
她不顾一切伸出手去抓住他的…
She threw caution to the wind and reached out and grabbed his..."
这是色情小说!
This is a dirty book!
菲比?
Phoebe?
嗨，罗斯
Oh, Ross, hi.
菲比，你在干什么? 抱歉，我有客人在
- Phoebe, what are you doing? - Sorry, I'm with a client right now.
菲比! 好吧，我们在外面谈
- Phoebe! - Okay, let's talk outside.
不好意思，这个仍会算在你的按摩时间里
Unfortunately, this time will be counted as part of your massage.
所以…
So try...
…思想尽量放松
...and think relaxing thoughts.
别碰我的恐龙
And don't touch any of my dinosaurs.
我知道它们很酷，但那是我的
I know they're cool, but they're mine.
你不可以在我家帮人家按摩
Phoebe, you can't massage people in my apartment.
我在莫妮卡和钱德家都可以
I did it at Monica and Chandler's.
他们知道吗?
And they knew about it?
好吧，罗斯，到底怎么回事?
Okay, Ross, what is this really about?
这是我家，我希望能自由出入
This is my home and I want to be able to come and go when I want.
我会找其他地方来做我其他的客人
I will find someplace else to do the rest of my appointments.
这有什么大不了的
I don't know what the big deal is.
我不要光着身子身上油油的陌生人在我家
I don't want naked, greasy strangers in my apartment...
当我想回家放松 拿一片拼图…我是说啤酒，冰啤酒
...when I want to kick back with a puzzle... Beer, cold beer.
嘿，乔伊，你好吗?
Hey, Joey. What are you doing?
扫地，怎么? 引起你的性趣吗?
Sweeping. Why? Does it turn you on?
不会
No.
如果我扫的是烟囱呢?
What if I was sweeping a chimney?
乔伊，你吃了我的面霜吗?
Joey, did you eat my face cream?
你去哪儿? 传教士要几小时后才会回家
Where are you going? The vicar won't be home for hours.
乔伊，你从哪儿学到那个字?
Joey, where did you learn that word?
你想是哪里
Where do you think...
柔达?
...Zelda?
你看了我的书? 对!
- You found my book?! - Yeah, I did!
乔伊，你到我房里干什么?
Joey, what are you doing going into my bedroom?
抱歉，我想去睡一下，我知道我不对 可是你有色情小说!
I'm sorry. I went in there to take a nap.I know I shouldn't have, but you got porn!
天哪，真想不到你会那样侵犯我的隐私权
God! I cannot believe you invaded my privacy like that!
柔达
Zelda.
现在你有点紧张 如果洗个牛奶浴可能就会放松多了
Now, you seem a little tense. Maybe you'll relax if I gave you a nice milk bath.
好的，你知道吗?
Okay, you know what?
我都不喜欢那个部分 噢，我喜欢
- I don't even like that part. - Oh, I do.
知道吗? 我不在乎 我不觉得我的书丢脸
You know what? I don't care. I'm not ashamed of my book.
女人享受一点情色没什么不对
There's nothing wrong with a woman enjoying a little erotica.
是女性性感的健康表达…
It's just a healthy expression of female sexuality...
顺便说一句，那是你永远都不会了解的
...which, by the way, is something that you will never understand.
你有色情小说
You got porn.
你好 菲比在吗?
- Hello. - Hi, is Phoebe here?
-不，今晚她不在 -真是的!
- No, she's out for the night. - Oh, great.
可以帮你忙吗?
Can I help you with something?
我不知道，你是按摩师吗?
I don't know. Are you a masseur?
是，我是
Yes, I am.
太好了! 爸?
Great! Dad?
谢谢你，一小时后我来接他
Thank you so much. I'll pick him up in an hour.
要我帮你吗?
You need help with that?
你父母听到你订婚一定很开心
Your parents must've been thrilled when you told them you were engaged.
哦，是啊，我应该打电话给他们
Oh, yeah. I should probably call them.
我记得我们刚订婚的时候
I remember when we first got engaged.
-我没听过这个故事 -爸，你不要…
- I've never heard that story. - Dad, you don't...
我让茱蒂怀孕了
Well, I'd gotten Judy pregnant.
我还不知道怎么发生的
I still don't know how.
你不知道怎么发生的? 你的狗以为我的避孕器是磨牙玩具
You don't know how? Your dog thought my diaphragm was a chew toy.
真感人的故事
What a sweet story.
至少你不是在五年级的万圣节宴会听到这故事的
At least you're not hearing it at your fifth grade Halloween party.
他们当时说要听吓人的故事
They wanted a scary story.
我们对婚礼计划书很兴奋
We're really excited about our wedding plans.
很快我们就要从莫妮卡婚礼基金提一大笔钱
I guess pretty soon we'll be making a big withdrawal from the Monica wedding fund.
-什么? -杰克，你告诉她，我做不到
- What? - You tell her, Jack. I can't do it.
你们有莫妮卡婚礼基金，对吧?
You have the wedding fund, don't you?
我们有，只是现在叫做“海滩别墅”
We have it. Only, now we call it "the beach house."
你把我的婚礼基金花在海滩别墅?
You spent my wedding fund on the beach house?
对不起，我们以为…
We're sorry. We assumed...
如果你30岁以后结婚，你会自己付的
...that if you got married after 30 you'd pay for it yourself.
你们买海滩别墅时我才23岁
You bought the beach house when I was 23.
你在海滩享受了7年好时光…
So you've had seven years of beach fun...
那可是无价的
...and you can't put a price on that.
我们觉得很抱歉
We do feel bad about this.
你和理查交往时我们又开始存钱
We saved again when you dated Richard...
结果你们闹翻了，我们重新装修了厨房
...then that went to hell, so we redid the kitchen.
那钱德呢?
What about Chandler?
我们以为钱德不会求婚
It was Chandler. We didn't think he'd propose.
很明显刚吃饭时，我的酒喝得不够
Clearly I did not start drinking enough at the start of the meal.
我不相信竟然没有钱让我结婚
I can't believe there's no money for my wedding.
也许还有，如果你爸没有…
Maybe, if your father hadrt tried...
在网上卖冰的话
...to sell ice over the Internet.
-那个主意看来很简单  -笨，杰克，只能用“笨”来形容
- It seemed like such a simple idea. - Stupid, Jack. The word is stupid.
够了，我不想再听了
Enough. I don't want to hear about it anymore.
钱德，祝你好运
Good luck, Chandler.
好，现在我要…
Okay, now I'm going to...
碰你了
...touch you.
好软
That's soft.
乔伊怎么老说扫烟囱和传教士?
Why does Joey keep talking about chimney sweeps and vicars?
可能在排演他的一场戏吧
I thinks he's just been rehearsing for an episode of his show.
因为听起来好像一本色情小说
Because it really sounds like a bad porn novel.
你的父母可能帮忙付吗?
Do you think your parents could help pay for it?
我不知道
I don't know.
我妈大部份的钱都花在她第四次的婚礼了
My mother spent most of her money on her fourth wedding.
剩下的钱她离婚要用
She's saving the rest for her divorce.
而我爸存的钱用在他每年一次的旅行…
And any extra cash my father has he saves for his yearly trips to...
桃利屋的（性感影星桃利・伯顿建设的主题公园）
...Dollywood.
你们吃饭发生什么事了? 我父母把婚礼基金花掉了
- What happened at dinner?- My parents spent the wedding fund.
我的天，你点了什么菜?
My God, what did you order?
等一下，没有婚礼基金? 太惨了
Wait, there's no money? Well, this is terrible.
你们只能在在社区的活动中心结婚了
You guys are gonna have to get married in, like, a rec center.
天哪，你说的没错
Oh, my God, you're right.
我们要过去6个人 才可以拿掉地板作游泳池
We're gonna have to be out by 6 so they can take out the floor for senior swim.
-亲爱的，没关系的 -不，有关系
- Honey, it's gonna be okay.- No, it's not gonna be okay.
-没有乐团，没有百合 -那很好啊
- No swing band, no lilies. - No, but that's good.
你不会想要百合的
You don't want lilies.
如果猫吃了百合就会死的
If a cat ate them, it would die.
什么? 我是说，你现在可以邀请猫了
- What?- I'm just saying, now you could invite cats.
没事的
It's gonna be okay.
你不需要有这种…
I mean, you don't need to have this...
意大利野宴
...rustic Italian feast.
你不需要这种订做的…
You don't need this custom-made...
帝国式腰线、公主型丝缎礼服
...empire-waisted, duchess satin gown.
你可以买现成的礼服
You can wear off-the-rack.
真的不会有问题的
It's really gonna be okay.
重要的是我们彼此相爱，要结婚了
The important thing is that we love each other and we're gonna get married.
你知不知道“现成的”是什么意思?
Do you even understand what "off-the-rack" means?
你为什么不自己付钱呢?
Why don't you pay for it yourself?
怎么付? 我没钱
How? I don't have any money.
-我有 -多少?
- Well, I have some. - How much?
将近有…
Well, close to...
-你开玩笑? -多少?
- Are you kidding me?! - How much?
-够办婚礼计划A -真的?
- Enough for wedding scenario A. - Really?
计划A有百合 必须有人为了猫毁掉这个计划，当然不是我
Scenario A has lilies. Someone's gonna have to break it to the cats and it won't be me.
你真好，努力存钱的人!
How great are you, you little saver!
正是理想婚礼的预算
This is exactly the budget of my dream wedding.
你们是天造地设的一对
You guys are so made for each other.
你不是要把所有的钱都花在婚礼上吧?
You're not suggesting that we spend all of the money on the wedding?
是啊
Yeah.
我花了六年存到这些…
Look, Mon, I've been saving this money for six years...
有些是将来要用的 不是都花在一场宴会上的
...and I kind of had some of it earmarked for the future, not just for a party.
钱德先生，你好啊
Hello, Mr. Chandler.
亲爱的，这是我们一生中最重要的一天
Sweetie, this is the most special day of our lives.
我知道，亲爱的 但我不要把钱都花在一场宴会上
I realize that, honey, but I'm not gonna spend all the money on one party.
亲爱的，我爱你
Honey, I love you.
但如果你再叫我们的婚礼一场宴会…
But if you call our wedding a party one more time...
你可能不会被邀请
...you may not get invited.
钱可以再赚，我们只结婚一次
We can always earn more money. We're only gonna get married once.
我了解，但我非常坚决，我的答案是不
I understand, but I have to put my foot down. The answer is no.
你很坚决?
You're gonna have to "put your foot down"?
对，我是
Yes, I am.
有钱和有一双坚定的手
Money and a firm hand.
终于是我可以认同的钱德了
Finally a Chandler I can get on board with.
-嘿，瑞秋 -乔伊
- Hey, Rach. - Joey.
有没有闻到烟昧?
Hey, Rach, do you smell smoke?
我懂了，烟，烟囱，扫烟囱的人，很好笑
I get it. Smoke, chimney, chimney sweep. Very funny. Ha, ha.
不，不，我说真的，你没闻到?
No, no, I'm serious. You don't smell it?
有东西着火了
Something's on fire.
我没闻到什么?
No, I don't smell anything.
你知道吗? 可能是你熊熊的欲火
Oh, you know what? It's probably just your burning loins.
-你们在讲什么? -没什么
- Hey, what are you guys talking about? - Nothing.
讨厌，咖啡冷了
Damn, this coffee's cold.
可以在你身上加温一下吗?
Do you mind if I heat this up on your loins?
乔伊，你竟然告诉了他…
You know, I cannot believe you told him. Joey...
我猜你在我们分手后买了那本书
So I guess you bought that book after we broke up.
是啊，因为第一本在我们交往时被翻烂了
Yeah, I did, because I wore out my first copy when I was with you.
是吗?
Oh, yeah?
我们交往时，我看了一大堆色情杂志
Well, when we were going out, I read tons of porno magazines.
怎么样?
What's up?
罗斯，你怎么可以 那样对待那一位老先生
Ross, how could you do that to an old man?
对不起，小姐们
Excuse me, ladies.
什么啊?
I'm sorry?
我的按摩客人，亚瑟
My massage client, Arthur.
他女儿说替我工作的一个人…
His daughter said some guy that worked for me...
替他做了很大奇怪的按摩
...gave him a really weird massage.
我做了很专业的按摩
I gave him an extremely professional massage.
他说你用木汤匙戳他
He said you poked at him with wooden spoons.
好吧，不是传统的按摩
Okay, so it wasn't a traditional massage.
可是我有用筷子为他指压按摩…
But I did give him acupressure with a pair of chopsticks...
温和地用拖把去角质
...and I gently exfoliated him with a mop.
他再也不会来了 你害我一星期少进帐八十元
Well, he's never coming back. You just cost me $80 a week.
是你的错，你没更改他约的时间
This is your fault. You didn't move his appointment.
我的错? 你不必替他按摩的
Oh, it's my fault? You didn't have to massage him.
你可以请他回去的
You could've sent him away.
你不必用玩具唐卡车（福特公司生产）在他背上策来滚去
You could've not rolled Tonka trucks up and down his back.
他说他很喜欢的!
He said he liked that!
你对，你对，对不起
You're right, you're right. I'm sorry.
你干嘛按摩一位老先生?
Dude, what are you massaging an old man for?
-他女儿很辣 -懂了
- His daughter was hot. - Gotcha.
罗斯，我每周真的很需要那80美元
Look, Ross, I really need that $80 every week.
你一定会找到另外一个客人的，菲比
I'm sure you'll find another massage client, Phoebe.
当然会了．不过在此之前 我会每周给你按摩…
Yeah, I'm sure I will too. But until then, I'm going to massage you every week...
-收费100美元 -不是说了80吗?
...for the price of $ 100. - You just said 80.
要我弄乱你的拼图吗?
You want me to mess up your puzzle?
一百就一百了
A hundred it is.
你好，柔达
Hello, Zelda.
-你要扮谁啊? -传教士
- Who are you supposed to be? - The vicar.
-你知道传教士是什么样的吗？ -就像一个守门员，对吗?
- Do you even know what a vicar is? - Like a goalie, right?
够了
Look, that's enough.
不要再说那个笑话了，我厌烦了
The joke's over. I'm sick of it.
你不是一辈子都在等那一刻欲火中烧吗?
You mean this isn't the sweet torment you've been waiting all your life for?
乔伊，正经点，好吗? 够了
Joey, I'm serious, all right? It's enough.
你讲那个愚蠢的笑话，含沙射影…
You make stupid jokes and sleazy innuendoes...
…一点都不好笑
...and it's just not funny anymore.
对不起，瑞秋，对不起
I'm sorry. Rach, I'm sorry.
也许我带你去谷仓会补偿你吧
Maybe I could make it up to you by taking you roughly in the barn.
好吧．你想做吗? 那就做吧
All right, that's it. You wanna do it? Let's do it.
没错．我要跟你做
That's right. I wanna do it with you.
来干一仗，你刚才说的没错
Been trying to fight it, but you just said all the right things.
是吗?
I did?
是的，我等了这么久，就是要你的身体
Yeah. Oh, I've been waiting so long to get on that body.
我的身体? 没错
- This body? - Yeah, that's right.
来吧，乔伊，跟我做爱吧
Come on, Joey, sex me up.
听起来你就像第7章屠夫的老婆
You're starting to sound like the butcher's wife in chapter seven.
来吧．别让我等了，脱衣服
Come on, now. Don't keep me waiting. Get those clothes off.
不过要戴着头盔 因为你将会激情上路
But I'd keep that helmet on, because you're in for a rough ride.
我不要．我好怕
I don't want to. I'm scared.
听着…
Listen...
我想过了
...l've been thinking.
要你把所有的钱花在婚礼上很不公平
It's not fair of me to ask you to spend all of your money on our wedding.
你很辛苦才赚来的
I mean, you work really hard for that.
-嗯 -好吧，你赚来的
- Well. - Well, you work for that.
我也想过了
Look, I've thought about it too.
对不起，我们应该把钱花在婚礼的
I'm sorry. I think we should spend all of the money on the wedding.
-真的? -对，我很坚决
- You do? - Yeah, I'm putting my foot down.
当我求婚时，我告诉你…
Look, when I proposed, I told you...
我会尽力让你快乐
...that I would do anything to make you happy.
如果办一场完美的婚礼，能让你开心…
And if having the perfect wedding makes you happy...
我们就这么做
...then that's what we're gonna do.
你真好
You are so sweet.
那未来怎么办呢?
What about the future and stuff?
管他呢
Forget about the future and stuff.
我们只生两个就好
So we only have two kids.
选一个我们最喜欢的让他去念大学
We'll pick our favorite and that one will get to go to college.
-你想过这些? -对
- Have you thought about that? - Yeah.
你本来要几个孩子?
How many kids were we gonna have?
四个，一个男孩 一对双胞胎女儿，再一个男孩
Four. A boy, twin girls and another boy.
你还想过什么?
What else did you think about?
还有我们要住的地方
Well, stuff like where we'd live, you know.
是在市郊的小房子
Like a small place outside the city...
我们的小孩可以学骑单车
...where our kids could learn to ride their bikes.
可以养只猫，脖子上挂着铃档…
We could have a cat that had a bell on its collar...
每次它跑出小门时都听得见铃声
...and we could hear it every time it ran through the little kitty door.
在车库上盖个房间，让乔伊养老
We'd have an apartment over the garage where Joey could grow old.
你知道吗?
You know what?
我不要一个盛大的婚礼
I don't want a big, fancy wedding.
你要的 不
- Sure you do. - No.
我要你刚刚说的每一样 我要一个婚姻
I want everything that you've just said. I want a marriage.
你确定?
You sure?
我好爱你 我爱你
- I love you so much. - I love you.
你刚说到将来的时候，你说猫
When you were talking about our future, you said cat.
你指的是狗，对不对?
But you meant dog, right?
对 好
- Yeah, totally. - Oh, good.
室内温度合适吗?
Room temperature okay?
很好．音乐声大吗? 不
- Excellent. Is the music too loud? - No.
好
Good.
-你干嘛? -噢，对不起
- What the hell are you doing? - Oh, I'm sorry.
你要用手的传统按摩吗?
Were you expecting a traditional massage with the hands?
好的
Fine.
开始放松
Now, just try to relax.